export const testData = [
  {
    id: 1,
    problem: 'How can we describe an array in the best possible way?',
    option: [
      'The Array shows a hierarchical structure.',
      'Arrays are immutable.',
      'Container that stores the elements of similar types',
      'The Array is not a data structure',
    ],
    answer: 'Container that stores the elements of similar types',
    tags: ['array', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    problem: 'Which of the following is the correct way of declaring an array?',
    option: [
      'int arr[10];', 'int arr;.', 'arr[10]', 'array arr[10];',
    ],
    answer: 'int arr[10];',
    tags: ['array','easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    problem: 'When the user tries to delete the element from the empty stack then the condition is said to be a __',
    option: [
      'Underflow', 'Garbage Collection', 'Overflow', 'None of the above',
    ],
    answer: 'Underflow',
    tags: ['stack','easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    problem: 'Which data structure is mainly used for implementing the recursive algorithm?',
    option: [
      'Queue', 'Stack', 'Binary Tree', 'Linked List',
    ],
    answer: 'Stack',
    tags: ['stack','recursion','medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    problem: 'Which of the following is the prefix form of A+B*C?',
    option: [
      'A+(BC*)', '+AB*C', 'ABC+*', '+A*BC',
    ],
    answer: '+A*BC',
    tags: ['stack', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    problem: 'Which one of the following is the correct way to increment the rear end in a circular queue?',
    option: [
      'rear =rear+1', '(rear+1) % max', '(rear % max) + 1', 'None of the above',
    ],
    answer: '(rear+1) % max',
    tags: ['queue', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    problem: 'Which one of the following is not the application of the Queue data structure?',
    option: [
      'Resource shared between various systems',
      'Data is transferred asynchronously',
      'Load balancing',
      'Balancing of symbols',
    ],
    answer: 'Balancing of symbols',
    tags: ['queue', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    problem: 'The necessary condition to be checked before deletion from the Queue is__',
    option: [
      'Overflow', 'Underflow', 'Rear Value', 'Front Value',
    ],
    answer: 'Underflow',
    tags: ['queue', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    problem: 'Which of the following is the time complexity to search an element in the linked list?',
    option: [
      'O(1)', 'O(n)', 'O(logn)', 'O(nlogn)',
    ],
    answer: 'O(n)',
    tags: ['linked_list', 'search', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    problem: 'Which of the following statement is not true about the doubly linked list?',
    option: [
      'We can traverse in both the directions.',
      'It requires extra space',
      'Implementation of doubly linked list is easier than the singly linked list',
      'It stores the addresses of the next and the previous node',
    ],
    answer: 'Implementation of doubly linked list is easier than the singly linked list',
    tags: ['linked_list', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    problem: 'What is the maximum number of children that a node can have in a binary tree?',
    option: [
      '3', '1', '4', '2',
    ],
    answer: '2',
    tags: ['tree', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    problem: 'Which of the following options is not true about the Binary Search tree?',
    option: [
      'The value of the left child should be less than the root node',
      'The value of the right child should be greater than the root node.',
      'The left and right sub trees should also be a binary search tree',
      'None of the above',
    ],
    answer: 'None of the above',
    tags: ['bst', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    problem: 'What is the maximum number of children that a node can have in a binary tree?',
    option: [
      '3', '1', '4', '2',
    ],
    answer: '2',
    tags: ['tree', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    problem: 'A connected planar graph having 6 vertices, 7 edges contains _____ regions',
    option: [
      '15', '3', '1', '11',
    ],
    answer: '3',
    tags: ['graph', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    problem: 'What is time complexity of binary search?',
    option: [
      'O(1)', 'O(n)', 'O(logn)', 'O(nlogn)',
    ],
    answer: 'O(logn)',
    tags: ['tree', 'binary_search', 'bst', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    problem: 'Given  Inorder traversal is { 4, 2, 1, 7, 5, 8, 3, 6 }, and  Preorder traversal is { 1, 2, 4, 3, 5, 7, 8, 6 }, find Postorder traversal for a tree.',
    option: [
      '4 2 7 8 5 6 3 1',
      '4 2 7 8 5 6 1 3',
      '8 2 7 6 5 4 3 1',
      '4 2 7 1 5 8 6 3',
    ],
    answer: '4 2 7 8 5 6 3 1',
    tags: ['tree', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    problem: 'The complexity of Bubble sort algorithm is',
    option: [
      'O(n)', 'O(n2)', 'O(logn)', 'O(nlogn)',
    ],
    answer: 'O(n2)',
    tags: ['sort', 'array', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    problem: 'In linear search algorithm the Worst case occurs when',
    option: [
      'The item is somewhere in the middle of the array',
      'The item is not in the array',
      'The item is the last element of array',
      'The item is the last element in the array or is not there at all',
    ],
    answer: 'The item is the last element in the array or is not there at all',
    tags: ['sort', 'array', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    problem: 'Which of the following trait of a hash function is most desirable?',
    option: [
      'It should cause less collisions',
      'It should cause more collisions',
      'It should be easy to implement',
      'It should occupy less space',
    ],
    answer: 'It should cause less collisions',
    tags: ['hash_table', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    problem: 'When inorder traversing a tree resulted in E A C K F H D B G, the preorder traversing would return',
    option: [
      'FAEKCDBHG', 'FAEKCDHGB', 'EAFKHDCBG', 'FEAKDCHBG',
    ],
    answer: 'FAEKCDHGB',
    tags: ['tree', 'hard'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 2,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    problem: 'Which of the following data-structures are indexed data-structures?',
    option: [
      'Linear arrays',
      'Linked List',
      'Both of above',
      'None of the above',
    ],
    answer: 'Linear arrays',
    tags: ['array', 'linked_list', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    problem: 'What is another name for the circular queue among the following options?',
    option: [
      'Square buffer', 'Rectangle buffer', 'Ring buffer', 'None of the above',
    ],
    answer: 'Ring buffer',
    tags: ['queue', 'circular_queue', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    problem: 'Which of the following principle does Queue use?',
    option: [
      'LIFO principle', 'FIFO principle', 'Linear tree', 'Ordered array',
    ],
    answer: 'FIFO principle',
    tags: ['queue', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    problem: 'Which one of the following is not the type of the Queue',
    option: [
      'Linear Queue', 'Circular Queue', 'Double ended Queue', 'Single ended Queue',
    ],
    answer: 'Single ended Queue',
    tags: ['queue', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    problem: 'The time complexity of enqueue operation in Queue is __',
    option: [
      'O(1)', 'O(n)', 'O(logn)', 'O(nlogn)',
    ],
    answer: 'O(1)',
    tags: ['queue', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    problem: 'Which one of the following is the correct way to increment the rear end in a circular queue?',
    option: [
      'rear =rear+1', '(rear+1) % max', '(rear % max) + 1', 'None of the above',
    ],
    answer: '(rear+1) % max',
    tags: ['queue', 'circular_queue', 'hard'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 2,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    problem: 'n the linked list implementation of queue, where will the new element be inserted?',
    option: [
      'At the middle position of the linked list',
      'At the head position of the linked list',
      'At the tail position of the linked list',
      'None of the above',
    ],
    answer: 'At the tail position of the linked list',
    tags: ['queue', 'linked_list', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    problem: 'How many Queues are required to implement a Stack?',
    option: [
      '3', '2', '1', '4',
    ],
    answer: '2',
    tags: ['queue', 'stack', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    problem: 'Which data structure is the best for implementing a priority queue?',
    option: [
      'Stack', 'Linked list', 'Array', 'Heap',
    ],
    answer: 'Heap',
    tags: ['queue', 'priority_queue', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    problem: 'A linear data structure in which insertion and deletion operations can be performed from both the ends is___',
    option: [
      'Queue', 'Deque', 'Priority queue', 'Circular queue',
    ],
    answer: 'Deque',
    tags: ['queue', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    problem: 'How can we define a AVL tree?',
    option: [
      'A tree which is binary search tree and height balanced tree.',
      'A tree which is a binary search tree but unbalanced tree.',
      'A tree with utmost two children',
      'A tree with utmost three children',
    ],
    answer: 'A tree which is binary search tree and height balanced tree.',
    tags: ['tree', 'avl_tree', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    problem: 'Which of the following satisfies the property of the Red Black tree?',
    option: [
      'A tree which is a binary search tree but not strictly balanced tree.',
      'A node must be either Red or Black in color and root node must be black.',
      'A tree with maximum three children',
      'Both a and b',
    ],
    answer: 'Both a and b',
    tags: ['tree', 'red_black_tree', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.javatpoint.com/data-structure-mcq',
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    problem: ' What is the number of edges present in a complete graph having n vertices?',
    option: [
      '(n*(n+1))/2', '(n*(n-1))/2', 'n', 'Information given is insufficient',
    ],
    answer: '(n*(n-1))/2',
    tags: ['graph', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-graph/',
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    problem: 'A graph with all vertices having equal degree is known as a __________',
    option: [
      'Multi Graph', 'Regular Graph', 'Simple Graph', 'Complete Graph',
    ],
    answer: 'Regular Graph',
    tags: ['graph', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-graph/',
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    problem: 'The time complexity to calculate the number of edges in a graph whose information in stored in form of an adjacency matrix is ____________',
    option: [
      'O(V)', 'O(E2)', 'O(E)', 'O(V2)',
    ],
    answer: 'O(V2)',
    tags: ['graph', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-adjacency-matrix/',
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    problem: 'If A[x+3][y+5] represents an adjacency matrix, which of these could be the value of x and y',
    option: [
      'x=5, y=3', 'x=3, y=5', ' x=3, y=3', 'x=5, y=5',
    ],
    answer: 'x=5, y=3',
    tags: ['graph', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-adjacency-matrix/',
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    problem: 'Space complexity for an adjacency list of an undirected graph having large values of V (vertices) and E (edges) is ___________',
    option: [
      'O(E)', 'O(V*V)', 'O(E+V)', 'O(V)',
    ],
    answer: 'O(E+V)',
    tags: ['graph', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-adjacency-list/',
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    problem: 'In which case adjacency list is preferred in front of an adjacency matrix?',
    option: [
      'Dense graph', 'Sparse graph', 'Adjacency list is always preferred', 'Complete graph',
    ],
    answer: 'Sparse graph',
    tags: ['graph', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-adjacency-list/',
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    problem: 'Dijkstra’s Algorithm will work for both negative and positive weights?',
    option: [
      'True', 'False', 'Insufficient information', 'Both b and c',
    ],
    answer: 'False',
    tags: ['graph', 'Dijkstra', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-directed-graph/',
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    problem: 'What is the maximum possible number of edges in a directed graph with no self loops having 8 vertices?',
    option: [
      '28', '64', '256', '56',
    ],
    answer: '56',
    tags: ['graph', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-directed-graph/',
  },
  {
    id: 41,
    problem: 'If the number of records to be sorted is small, then …… sorting can be efficient.',
    option: [
      'Merge ', 'Heap', 'Selection', 'Bubble',
    ],
    answer: 'Selection',
    tags: ['sorting', 'selection_sort', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.siteforinfotech.com/2014/12/mcq-on-searching-sorting-algorithm-data-structure.html',
  },
  {
    id: 42,
    problem: 'The complexity of the sorting algorithm measures the …… as a function of the number n of items to be sorter.',
    option: [
      'average time', 'running time', 'average-case complexity', 'case-complexity',
    ],
    answer: 'running time',
    tags: ['sorting', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.siteforinfotech.com/2014/12/mcq-on-searching-sorting-algorithm-data-structure.html',
  },
  {
    id: 43,
    problem: 'The Average case occurs in the linear search algorithm ……….',
    option: [
      'when the item is somewhere in the middle of the array',
      'when the item is not the array at all',
      'when the item is the last element in the array',
      'Item is the last element in the array or item is not there at all',
    ],
    answer: 'when the item is somewhere in the middle of the array',
    tags: ['searching', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.siteforinfotech.com/2014/12/mcq-on-searching-sorting-algorithm-data-structure.html',
  },
  {
    id: 44,
    problem: 'The complexity of merge sort algorithm is ……',
    option: [
      'O(n)', 'O(logn)', 'O(n2)', 'O(n logn)',
    ],
    answer: 'O(n logn)',
    tags: ['sorting', 'easy', 'merge_sort'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.siteforinfotech.com/2014/12/mcq-on-searching-sorting-algorithm-data-structure.html',
  },
  {
    id: 45,
    problem: '………. is putting an element in the appropriate place in a sorted list yields a larger sorted order list.',
    option: [
      'Insertion', 'Extraction', 'Selection', 'Distribution',
    ],
    answer: 'Insertion',
    tags: ['sorting', 'medium', 'insertion_sort'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.siteforinfotech.com/2014/12/mcq-on-searching-sorting-algorithm-data-structure.html',
  },
  {
    id: 46,
    problem: '………… is the method used by card sorter.',
    option: [
      'Radix sort', 'Insertion', 'Heap', 'Quick',
    ],
    answer: 'Radix sort',
    tags: ['sorting', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.siteforinfotech.com/2014/12/mcq-on-searching-sorting-algorithm-data-structure.html',
  },
  {
    id: 47,
    problem: 'Which of the following sorting algorithm is of priority queue sorting type?',
    option: [
      'Bubble sort', 'Insertion sort', 'Merge sort', 'Selection sort',
    ],
    answer: 'Selection sort',
    tags: ['priority_queue', 'queue', 'medium', 'selection_sort'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.siteforinfotech.com/2014/12/mcq-on-searching-sorting-algorithm-data-structure.html',
  },
  {
    id: 48,
    problem: 'Which of the following is not the required condition for a binary search algorithm?',
    option: [
      'The list must be sorted',
      'There should be direct access to the middle element in any sublist',
      'There must be a mechanism to delete and/or insert elements in the list.',
      'Number values should only be present',
    ],
    answer: 'There must be a mechanism to delete and/or insert elements in the list.',
    tags: ['searching', 'binary_search', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.siteforinfotech.com/2014/12/mcq-on-searching-sorting-algorithm-data-structure.html',
  },
  {
    id: 49,
    problem: 'Partition and exchange sort is ……..',
    option: [
      'quick sort', 'tree sort', 'heap sort', 'bubble sort',
    ],
    answer: 'quick sort',
    tags: ['sorting', 'quick_sort', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.siteforinfotech.com/2014/12/mcq-on-searching-sorting-algorithm-data-structure.html',
  },
  {
    id: 50,
    problem: ' An un weighted, connected or disconnected is a ____',
    option: [
      'weighted graph', 'unweighted graph', 'simple graph', 'none of these',
    ],
    answer: 'simple graph',
    tags: ['graph', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://t4tutorials.com/graph-algorithms-solved-mcqs-with-answers/',
  },
  {
    id: 51,
    problem: 'Which of the following means computing the reachibility of all the vertices?',
    option: [
      'transitive hull', 'safest path', 'minimum distance', 'maximum distance',
    ],
    answer: 'transitive hull',
    tags: ['graph', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://t4tutorials.com/graph-algorithms-solved-mcqs-with-answers/',
  },
  {
    id: 52,
    problem: 'Why graph traversal is difficult than tree traversal ',
    option: [
      'because tree have root', 'because tree is binary', 'because tree is undefined', 'all of these',
    ],
    answer: 'because tree have root',
    tags: ['graph', 'tree', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://t4tutorials.com/graph-algorithms-solved-mcqs-with-answers/',
  },
  {
    id: 53,
    problem: 'How quick sort partition an array ?',
    option: [
      'double element', 'pivot element', 'couple element', 'none of these',
    ],
    answer: 'pivot element',
    tags: ['sorting', 'quick_sort', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://t4tutorials.com/graph-algorithms-solved-mcqs-with-answers/',
  },
  {
    id: 54,
    problem: 'We use a circular linked list for stack as well as for …',
    option: [
      'binary tree', 'queue', 'heap', 'array',
    ],
    answer: 'queue',
    tags: ['linked_list', 'queue', 'circular_linked_list', 'stack', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://t4tutorials.com/graph-algorithms-solved-mcqs-with-answers/',
  },
  {
    id: 55,
    problem: 'What is the result if total time is bound of in prim’s algorithm?',
    option: [
      'O(m+n logn)', 'O(m logn)', 'O(nlogn)', 'none of these',
    ],
    answer: 'O(m+n logn)',
    tags: ['graph', 'prim', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://t4tutorials.com/graph-algorithms-solved-mcqs-with-answers/',
  },
  {
    id: 56,
    problem: 'If there are more than 1 topological sorting of a DAG is possible, which of the following is true.',
    option: [
      'Many Hamiltonian paths are possible',
      'No Hamiltonian path is possible',
      'Exactly 1 Hamiltonian path is possible',
      'Given information is insufficient to comment anything',
    ],
    answer: 'No Hamiltonian path is possible',
    tags: ['sorting', 'topological_sort', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'http://www.allindiaexams.in/engineering/cse/data-structure-mcq/graph/2',
  },
  {
    id: 57,
    problem: 'A connected planar graph having 6 vertices, 7 edges contains _____________ regions.',
    option: [
      '15', '3', '1', '11',
    ],
    answer: '3',
    tags: ['graph', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'http://www.allindiaexams.in/engineering/cse/data-structure-mcq/graph/2',
  },
  {
    id: 58,
    problem: 'What is time complexity to check if a string(length S1) is a substring of another string(length S2) stored in a Directed Acyclic Word Graph, given S2 is greater than S1?',
    option: [
      'O(S1)', 'O(S2)', 'O(S1+S2)', 'O(1)',
    ],
    answer: 'O(S1)',
    tags: ['graph', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'http://www.allindiaexams.in/engineering/cse/data-structure-mcq/graph/2',
  },
  {
    id: 59,
    problem: 'In a max-heap, element with the greatest key is always in the which node?',
    option: [
      'Leaf node', 'First node of left sub tree', 'root node', 'First node of right sub tree',
    ],
    answer: 'root node',
    tags: ['heap', 'tree', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-heap/',
  },
  {
    id: 60,
    problem: 'What is the complexity of adding an element to the heap.',
    option: [
      'O(log n)', 'O(h)', 'O(log n) & O(h)', 'O(n)',
    ],
    answer: 'O(log n) & O(h)',
    tags: ['heap', 'tree', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-heap/',
  },
  {
    id: 61,
    problem: 'Heap can be used as ________________',
    option: [
      'Priority queue', 'Stack', 'A decreasing order array', 'Normal Array',
    ],
    answer: 'Priority queue',
    tags: ['heap', 'priority_queue', 'tree', 'queue', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-heap/',
  },
  {
    id: 62,
    problem: 'An array consists of n elements. We want to create a heap using the elements. The time complexity of building a heap will be in order of',
    option: [
      'O(n*n*logn)', 'O(n*logn)', 'O(n*n)', 'O(n *logn *logn)',
    ],
    answer: 'O(n*logn)',
    tags: ['heap', 'tree', 'hard'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 2,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-heap/',
  },
  {
    id: 63,
    problem: ' ___________ is a self-adjusting version of a leftist heap',
    option: [
      'Rightist heap', 'Skew heap', 'd-heap', 'Binary heap',
    ],
    answer: 'Skew heap',
    tags: ['heap', 'tree', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/skew-heap-multiple-choice-questions-answers-mcqs/',
  },
  {
    id: 64,
    problem: 'The relationship of skew heaps to leftist heaps is analogous to that of?',
    option: [
      'Splay tree and AVL tree',
      'Red black tree and AVL tree',
      'Binary tree and Splay tree',
      'Binary tree and Red black tree',
    ],
    answer: 'Splay tree and AVL tree',
    tags: ['heap', 'tree', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/skew-heap-multiple-choice-questions-answers-mcqs/',
  },
  {
    id: 65,
    problem: 'What is the fundamental operation performed in skew heaps?',
    option: [
      'intersection', 'difference', 'merging', 'sorting',
    ],
    answer: 'merging',
    tags: ['heap', 'tree', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/skew-heap-multiple-choice-questions-answers-mcqs/',
  },
  {
    id: 66,
    problem: 'How many types of the merge are available in skew heaps?',
    option: [
      '1', '2', '3', '4',
    ],
    answer: '2',
    tags: ['heap', 'tree', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/skew-heap-multiple-choice-questions-answers-mcqs/',
  },
  {
    id: 67,
    problem: 'Descending priority queue can be implemented using ______',
    option: [
      'max heap', 'min heap', 'min-max heap', 'trie',
    ],
    answer: 'max heap',
    tags: ['heap', 'tree', 'priority_queue', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/min-max-heap-multiple-choice-questions-answers-mcqs/',
  },
  {
    id: 68,
    problem: 'Which one of the following array elements represents a binary min heap?',
    option: [
      '12 10 8 25 14 17',
      '8 10 12 25 14 17',
      '25 17 14 12 10 8',
      '14 17 25 10 12 8',
    ],
    answer: '8 10 12 25 14 17',
    tags: ['heap', 'tree', 'hard'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 2,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/min-max-heap-multiple-choice-questions-answers-mcqs/',
  },
  {
    id: 69,
    problem: 'In general, the index of the first element in an array is __________',
    option: [
      '0', '-1', '2', '1',
    ],
    answer: '0',
    tags: ['array', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-array-array-operations/',
  },
  {
    id: 70,
    problem: 'Elements in an array are accessed _____________',
    option: [
      'randomly', 'sequentially', 'exponentially', 'logarithmically',
    ],
    answer: 'randomly',
    tags: ['array', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-array-array-operations/',
  },
  {
    id: 71,
    problem: 'Assuming int is of 4bytes, what is the size of int arr[15];?',
    option: [
      '15', '19', '11', '60',
    ],
    answer: '60',
    tags: ['array', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-array-array-operations/',
  },
  {
    id: 72,
    problem: 'When does the ArrayIndexOutOfBoundsException occur?',
    option: [
      'Compile-time', 'Run-time', 'Not an error', 'Not an exception at all',
    ],
    answer: 'Run-time',
    tags: ['array', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-array-array-operations/',
  },
  {
    id: 73,
    problem: 'Which of the following concepts make extensive use of arrays?',
    option: [
      'Binary trees', 'Scheduling of processes', 'Caching', 'Spatial locality',
    ],
    answer: 'Spatial locality',
    tags: ['array', 'hard'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 2,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-array-array-operations/',
  },
  {
    id: 74,
    problem: 'What data structure would you mostly likely see in non recursive implementation of a recursive algorithm?',
    option: [
      'Linked List', 'Stack', 'Queue', 'Tree',
    ],
    answer: 'Stack',
    tags: ['stack', 'easy'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 0,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-interview-questions-answers/',
  },
  {
    id: 75,
    problem: 'The postfix form of the expression (A+ B)*(C*D- E)*F / G is?',
    option: [
      'AB+ CD*E – FG /**',
      'AB + CD* E – F **G /',
      'AB + CD* E – *F *G /',
      'AB + CDE * – * F *G /',
    ],
    answer: 'AB + CD* E – *F *G /',
    tags: ['stack', 'hard'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 2,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-interview-questions-answers/',
  },
  {
    id: 76,
    problem: 'The postfix form of A*B+C/D is?',
    option: [
      '*AB/CD+', 'AB*CD/+', 'A*BC+/D', 'ABCD+/*',
    ],
    answer: 'AB*CD/+',
    tags: ['stack', 'hard'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 2,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-interview-questions-answers/',
  },
  {
      id: 77,
      problem: 'The Depth First Search traversal of a graph will result into?',
      option: [
        'Linked List', 'Tree', 'Graph with back edges', 'Array',
      ],
      answer: 'Tree',
      tags: ['dfs', 'graph', 'easy'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-depth-first-search/',
  },
  {
    id: 78,
    problem: ' The prefix form of an infix expression (p + q) – (r * t) is?',
    option: [
      '+ pq – *rt', '– +pqr * t', '– +pq * rt', ' – + * pqrt',
    ],
    answer: '– +pq * rt',
    tags: ['stack', 'hard'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 2,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-interview-questions-answers/',
  },
  {
    id: 79,
    problem: 'In the worst case, the number of comparisons needed to search a singly linked list of length n for a given element is?',
    option: [
      'log2 n', ' n/2', 'log2 n – 1', 'n',
    ],
    answer: 'n',
    tags: ['linked_list', 'medium'],
    total_submission: 0,
    correct_submission: 0,
    difficulty: 1,
    link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-experienced/',
  },
  {
      id: 80,
      problem: 'Which of the following application makes use of a circular linked list?',
      option: [
        'Undo operation in a text editor',
        'Recursive function calls',
        'Allocating CPU to resources',
        'Implement Hash Tables',
      ],
      answer: 'Allocating CPU to resources',
      tags: ['circular_linked_list', 'easy'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-circular-linked-lists/',
    },
    {
      id: 81,
      problem: 'Which of the following is false about a circular linked list?',
      option: [
        'Every node has a successor',
        'Time complexity of inserting a new node at the head of the list is O(1)',
        'Time complexity for deleting the last node is O(n)',
        'We can traverse the whole circular linked list by starting from any point',
      ],
      answer: 'Time complexity of inserting a new node at the head of the list is O(1)',
      tags: ['circular_linked_list', 'easy'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-circular-linked-lists/',
    },
    {
      id: 82,
      problem: 'What differentiates a circular linked list from a normal linked list?',
      option: [
        'You cannot have the ‘next’ pointer point to null in a circular linked list',
        'It is faster to traverse the circular linked list',
        'You may or may not have the ‘next’ pointer point to null in a circular linked list',
        'Head node is known in circular linked list',
      ],
      answer: 'You may or may not have the ‘next’ pointer point to null in a circular linked list',
      tags: ['circular_linked_list', 'easy'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-circular-linked-lists/',
    },
    {
      id: 83,
      problem: 'What is a dequeue?',
      option: [
        'A queue with insert/delete defined for both front and rear ends of the queue',
        'A queue implemented with a doubly linked list',
        'A queue implemented with both singly and doubly linked lists',
        'A queue with insert/delete defined for front side of the queue',
      ],
      answer: 'A queue with insert/delete defined for both front and rear ends of the queue',
      tags: ['dequeue', 'easy'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-double-ended-queue/',
    },
    {
      id: 84,
      problem: 'What are the applications of dequeue?',
      option: [
        'A-Steal job scheduling algorithm',
        'Can be used as both stack and queue',
        'To find the maximum of all sub arrays of size k',
        'To avoid collision in hash tables',
      ],
      answer: 'To avoid collision in hash tables',
      tags: ['dequeue', 'easy'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-double-ended-queue/',
    },
    {
      id: 85,
      problem: 'What is the time complexity of deleting from the rear end of the dequeue implemented with a singly linked_list?',
      option: [
        'O(nlogn)', 'O(logn)', 'O(n)', 'O(n2)',
      ],
      answer: 'O(n)',
      tags: ['dequeue', 'linked_list', 'medium'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 1,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-double-ended-queue/',
    },
    {
      id: 86,
      problem: 'Why is implementation of stack operations on queues not feasible for a large dataset (Asssume the number of elements in the stack to be n)?',
      option: [
        'Because of its time complexity O(n)',
        'Because of its time complexity O(log(n))',
        'Extra memory is not required',
        'There are no problems',
      ],
      answer: 'Because of its time complexity O(n)',
      tags: ['stack', 'queue', 'hard'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 2,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-queue-using-stacks/',
    },
    {
      id: 87,
      problem: 'Given only a single array of size 10 and no other memory is available. Which of the following operation is not feasible to implement (Given only push and pop operation)?',
      option: [
        'Push', 'Pop', 'Enqueue', 'Returntop',
      ],
      answer: 'Enqueue',
      tags: ['stack', 'queue', 'hard'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 2,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-queue-using-stacks/',
    },
    {
      id: 88,
      problem: 'To implement a stack using queue(with only enqueue and dequeue operations), how many queues will you need?',
      option: [
        '1', '2', '3', '4',
      ],
      answer: '2',
      tags: ['stack', 'queue', 'medium'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 1,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-stack-using-queues/',
    },
    {
      id: 89,
      problem: 'How will you implement dynamic arrays in Java?',
      option: [
        'Set', 'Map', 'HashMap', 'List',
      ],
      answer: 'List',
      tags: ['array', 'medium'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 1,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-dynamic-array/',
    },
    {
      id: 90,
      problem: 'Which of the following is a disadvantage of dynamic arrays?',
      option: [
        'Locality of reference', 'Data cache utilization', 'Random access', 'Memory leak',
      ],
      answer: 'Memory leak',
      tags: ['array', 'medium'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 1,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-dynamic-array/',
    },
    {
      id: 91,
      problem: 'What is order of resultant heap after merging two tree of order k?',
      option: [
        '2*k', 'k+1', 'k*k', 'k+logk',
      ],
      answer: 'k+1',
      tags: ['heap', 'tree', 'medium'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: '',
    },
    {
      id: 92,
      problem: 'The algorithms like merge sort, quick sort and binary search are based on',
      option: [
        'Greedy algorithm', 'Divide and Conquer algorithm', 'Hash table', 'Parsing',
      ],
      answer: 'Divide and Conquer algorithm',
      tags: ['sorting', 'easy'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://mcqslearn.com/faqs/data-structures/divide-and-conquer-exam-questions-and-answers.php',
    },
    {
      id: 93,
      problem: 'Kruskal’s algorithm is used to ______',
      option: [
        'find minimum spanning tree',
        'find single source shortest path',
        'find all pair shortest path algorithm',
        'traverse the graph',
      ],
      answer: 'find minimum spanning tree',
      tags: ['graph', 'easy', 'kruskal'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/kruskals-algorithm-multiple-choice-questions-answers-mcqs/',
    },
    {
      id: 94,
      problem: 'Which of the following is false about the Kruskal’s algorithm?',
      option: [
        'It is a greedy algorithm',
        'It constructs MST by selecting edges in increasing order of their weights',
        'It can accept cycles in the MST',
        'It uses union-find data structure',
      ],
      answer: 'It can accept cycles in the MST',
      tags: ['graph', 'medium', 'kruskal'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 1,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/kruskals-algorithm-multiple-choice-questions-answers-mcqs/',
    },
    {
      id: 95,
      problem: 'The Bellmann Ford algorithm returns _______ value.',
      option: [
        'Boolean', 'Integer', 'String', 'Double',
      ],
      answer: 'Boolean',
      tags: ['bellmann', 'graph', 'easy'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/bellman-ford-algorithm-multiple-choice-questions-answers-mcqs/',
    },
    {
      id: 96,
      problem: 'What is the running time of Bellmann Ford Algorithm?',
      option: [
        'O(V)', 'O(V2)', 'O(ElogV)', 'O(VE)',
      ],
      answer: 'O(VE)',
      tags: ['bellmann', 'graph', 'easy'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/bellman-ford-algorithm-multiple-choice-questions-answers-mcqs/',
    },
    {
      id: 97,
      problem: 'What is the basic principle behind Bellmann Ford Algorithm?',
      option: [
        'Interpolation', 'Extrapolation', 'Regression', 'Relaxation',
      ],
      answer: 'Relaxation',
      tags: ['bellmann', 'graph', 'medium'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/bellman-ford-algorithm-multiple-choice-questions-answers-mcqs/',
    },
    {
      id: 98,
      problem: 'When the Breadth First Search of a graph is unique?',
      option: [
        'Finding shortest path between two nodes',
        'Finding bipartiteness of a graph',
        'GPS navigation system',
        'Path Finding',
      ],
      answer: 'Path Finding',
      tags: ['bfs', 'easy'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-breadth-first-search/',
    },
    {
      id: 99,
      problem: 'In BFS, how many times a node is visited?',
      option: [
        'Once', 'Twice', 'Equivalent to number of indegree of the node', 'Thrice',
      ],
      answer: 'Equivalent to number of indegree of the node',
      tags: ['bfs', 'easy', 'graph'],
      total_submission: 0,
      correct_submission: 0,
      difficulty: 0,
      link: 'https://www.sanfoundry.com/data-structure-questions-answers-breadth-first-search/',
    }
]
